旧金山飞来的530航班
Flight 530 from San Francisco,
你可以着陆了 机长
you're cleared for landing, Captain.
- 对不起 我不懂西班牙语  - 第一次到西班牙？
- Sorry, I don't speak Spanish.  - First time in Spain?
是啊 第一次到西班牙 我的行李在哪儿？
Yeah, first time in Spain. Where's my luggage?
不幸 它还在旧金山呢
Unfortunately, it's still in San Francisco.
太棒了
Fantastic.
赛莉 是我
Sally, it's me.
你打电话给航空公司 告诉他们把我的包留在旧金山
Can you call the airline and tell them to leave my bags in San Francisco?
他们到这儿之前 我就回去了 谢谢
I'll be back before they get here, anyway. Thanks.
威尔
Will?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
我以为乔许回来
I was... I was expecting Josh.
他还在船上睡觉呢 时差
He's asleep on the boat. Jet lag.
- 回去偷袭他一下 很高兴见到你  - 很高兴见到你
- Hit him all of a sudden. Good to see you.  - Good to see you.
工作怎么样？
How's the posting?
有一阵儿非常好
Best in a while.
有个福音四重奏巡演到这儿大约六个星期
Had a gospel quartet come through here for about six weeks,
然后俄勒冈州立大学的毕加索专家
and then a Picasso expert from Oregon State.
西班牙怎么会想听俄勒冈的毕加索专家的意见？
Why on earth would Spain want to hear from a Picasso expert from Oregon?
不同的观点
A different perspective.
对不起 稍等
Sorry, hold on.
喂？
Hello?
可以过几个小时给您回电话吗？
Look, could I call you back in a few hours?
- 好 再见
- Okay, bye. Bye.  - Bye.
一个电话 爸爸
One call, Dad.
这个假期 真不是离开公司的好时机
This vacation, it's just a real bad time for me to be away from the company.
你妈妈很高兴这个假期 威尔
Your mother's pretty happy about this vacation, Will.
威尔？
Will?
喔! 妈!
Oh! Mmm!
- 你气色很好 妈妈  - 谢谢你带菜回来 老公
- You look great, Mom.  -  Thanks for the groceries, hon.
你是怎么那么轻松？
How come you're so relaxed?
嗯 这是因为我们终于来了
Well, that's 'cause we're all finally here.
你的航班怎样？
How was your flight?
飞机起飞 飞过去 降落
The plane went up, flew straight across, went down again.
有个维诺小浴缸就全好了
Nothing a small bathtub of vino won't fix.
我们更好的  先去换件衣服吧
We can do better than that. Now, why don't you get that suit off?
你穿的这件像个手风琴  你的行李呢？
It looks like an accordion on you. Where's your luggage?
它好像还没和金门大桥告别完呢
Apparently it's still saying goodbye to the Golden Gate Bridge.
哦 上帝呀
Oh! For heaven's sake. Uh...
还好 这儿有一些是你去年来丢下的衣服
Well, there's some clothes you left behind from last year's trip.
干嘛不去换上呢？
Why don't you put those on?
等你换好了 我给你一杯里奥哈
I'll have a nice glass of Rioja waiting for you when you're ready.
看我说什么来着？
See what I mean?
我来的时候 她说 “冰箱里有啤酒”
When I got here, she was like, "Beer's in the fridge."
妈妈总是最喜欢你
Mom always liked you best.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
看看这是谁呀
Look who's here.
达拉 这是威尔 好兄弟
Dara, this is Will. The good brother.
老是对大家讲他是独子的那个
The one who used to tell everybody he was an only child.
只是在生了乔许以后
Only after Josh was born.
去哥斯拉那一趟怎么样？
How was the ride with Godzilla?
没血腥 没傻瓜  哦
No blood, no foul. Yeah.
放松点儿 就一个星期
Well, just take it nice and easy. It's only a week.
我觉得你们爸爸挺好的
I think your dad's a sweetie.
她在苏联孤儿院长大的
She grew up in a Soviet orphanage.
好吧 我去换衣服
Well, I gotta get changed.
那不挺好吗
That's not bad.
但是在政府工作 就必须忍受官僚
But it's a government job. You have to tolerate the bureaucracy.
政府让你做什么你就做什么 所以没人喜欢
You move when the government tells you to move, so not everybody likes it.
是呀 我也不喜欢
Yeah, I'm not sure I liked it.
乔许和我从来没有相同的连续两年以上的朋友
Josh and I never got to have the same friends for more than two years in a row.
更不用说十八年里生活过十二个国家
Not to mention we lived in 12 different countries over 18 years.
好的一面是 为我们学会了十五种当地的体育项目
But the best thing is we learned about 15 weird local sports.
好了 老哥
Excuse me, my man.
我们在喀麦隆一起打篮球练田径 记得吗？
We both played basketball and ran track in the Comoros, remember?
学校里几乎没人超过一米六
Although no one in the school was over 5'3",
无论我们到哪儿 威尔都是全明星
and Will was pretty much the all-star everywhere we went.
哇 太好了
Wow! Well done.
嗯 怎么样？
Mmm. Got it?
我想告诉你们我太高兴了
Before we start, I just want to say how happy I am
我们终于又聚在一起了
that we're all finally together around a table again.
我都没意识到我有多想念这个
I didn't realize how much I'd missed this.
为家  好
To family. Nice.
为家
To family.
看上去很不错
This looks fantastic.
我的山洞人今天早上刚抓的
My caveman caught it this morning.
你抓的鱼 苏先生？
You fish, Mr. Shaw?
是 他抓的鱼
Yeah, he fishes.
- 哦 同志们  - 他抓鱼 他抓的鱼
-  Oh, guys.  - He fishes. He fishes.
- 哦 同志们请严肃点儿  - 我想听这里面的故事
- No, guys, seriously, please.  - Come on! I want to hear this story.
- 鱼叉捕鱼是他强项  - 对不起
-  Spear-fishing, actually, is his forte.  - Excuse me.
我必许接一下 很重要
I got to take this. Important.
不许再讲这些故事了 否则我开始讲你们的
No more of those stories or I'll start telling some of yours.
你今晚睡哪儿？  你们没睡一起吧？
Where are you sleeping tonight? You guys aren't sleeping together, are you?
哦 爸
Jesus, Dad.
如果我们一起做 我相信我们双方都会获利
If we work together on this, I'm sure it's going to be beneficial for both of us.
星期四？
This Thursday?
我现在国外
I'm out of the country, so...
明白
I understand.
好 再见
Okay. Bye.
- 挺危险的吧  - 是 他那次尤其危险
-  Quite dangerous.  - Yeah, in his case it was quite dangerous.
- 他来了 嘘  - 可怜的威尔
- Here he comes. Shh!  - Poor Will.
- 这是他的小秘密
- Poor Will.  - It's just his little secret.
这个段子会在家族里流传一段时间呢
That story's going to stay in the family for a while.
它哪儿也去不了
It's not going anywhere.
讲讲吧
Please, tell me. Come on.
乔许 停
Josh, that's enough.
- 认真的 停 别讲了  - 威尔是那个渔夫
- No, guys, seriously, please. Don't.  - Will is the fisherman.
好吧 在他们讲出任何夸张的段子之前
All right, before they go off on any kind of fantastic story,
真实发生的是
what really happened was that he took me out
我才十岁的时候 他带我去叉鱼
when I'm 10 years old spear-fishing, ten years old,
结果我叉到自己脚蹼
and I spear my own flipper.
每个人都觉得很搞笑
And everyone finds this hilarious.
- 就这故事？  - 就这故事
- That's the story?  - That's the story.
他整夜都在哭
He cried all night.
几乎叉到脚  一直哭到睡着
He could've speared his foot.  He cried himself to sleep.
威尔 哭的声音 乔许 可以告诉你
Will would make this noise when he cried. Josh could tell you.
- 就像小声抽  - 很好笑
- It's like a little wuffling sound.  - Really funny. Really...
实际上 你们知道吗 今天不是开玩笑的日子
Actually, you know what? This is not the day for a joke.
- 我不能留下一个星期了  - 什么？
- I don't know if I can stay the week.  - What?
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry, Mom.
我刚知道
I have just found out
我公司正式破产了
my company is officially bankrupt.
什么？
What?
- 对不起  - 你在说什么？
-  I'm sorry.  - What are you talking about?
威尔？
Will?
对不起 我在饭桌上这样子
I'm sorry I went off at you at dinner.
我很难过你经历这样的困难
I'm sorry you're going through such a difficult time.
谢谢
Thank you.
明天的风会不错
It'll be a good wind tomorrow.
是
Yeah.
准备好出发吧
Get ready to come about!
威尔？
Will?
威尔!
Will!
绑紧船帆
Tighter on that boom!
紧点儿 威尔!
Tighter, Will!
知道了
I heard you the first time.
乔许, 我们在这下锚
Josh, we'll anchor here!
威尔？
Will?
威尔!
Will!
过来一下
When you get a minute.
把住 冲着风
Keep it into the wind.
威尔! 冲着风
Will! Into the wind!
头冲着风
Head it into the wind!
达拉!
Dara!
哦 上帝呀 你没事吧
Oh, my God, are you okay?
- 让我看看  - 我没事
- Let me take a look.  - Yeah, I'm okay.
- 上帝呀  - 没事 没事
- Oh, my God!  - I'm okay. I'm okay.
她没事吧？  你没事吧？
Is she okay? You all right?
- 没大事 会好的  - 是 没关系
-  You'll be fine.  - Yeah, I'm fine.
- 该死的手机  - 嘿！不是开玩笑的？
- Damn phone!  - Hey! Are you kidding me?
- 威尔, 你疯了吗？  - 没有！
- Will, have you lost your mind?  - No!
- 闭嘴  - 你扔的是我的饭碗
- Shut up!  - That's my career you threw away there!
- 船甲板上那个女孩头都打破了  - 见鬼
- There is a girl on the deck of the boat...  - What the hell?
马丁! 够了
...with her head cut open!  Martin! Enough!
我没事 真的没事
I'm okay! Seriously.
我需要进城 需要带东西吗？
I'm going into town. Anybody need anything?
找点儿杀菌药 药店会有的
Try to find some antiseptic. The pharmacy should have some.
好 我需要点儿现金
Okay, I'm gonna need some cash.
快回来 威尔
Hurry back, Will.
谢谢
Gracias.
我爱你
I love you.
- 我来 小心  - 好
- I got it. Be careful.  - Okay.
嘿 你看见船去哪儿了吗？
Hey. Did you see where that boat went?
你们谁看见船了？帆船？没有？
Guys, any of you see a boat? Like, a sailboat? No?
妈妈？
Mom?
求你帮帮忙 我们家出事了
Please, you gotta help me. Something's happened to my family.
什么？
What?
嘿！我们家出事了！
Hey! Something's happened to my family!
我的船毁了 人都不见了
My boat's been ripped to shit and they're gone!
- 我是皮拉罗警长 你是？  - 威尔 苏
- I'm Captain Pizarro. You are?  - I'm Will Shaw.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
带我去船上
Take me to the boat.
- 那是谁呀？  - 苏先生 镇静
- Who the hell is that?  - Please, Mr. Shaw, relax.
威尔 可以叫你威尔吗？
Will. Can I call you Will?
你怎么知道我名字？
How do you know my name?
你母亲告诉我的
Your mother told me.
- 她在哪儿？  - 我可以带你去
- Where is she?  - I can take you to her.
还有你家里其他人 来吧
And the rest of your family. Come on.
不 嘿！
No, hey!
- 来吧！  - 不 不 嘿！
- Hey! Come on!  - No, no! Hey!
- 来吧！  - 嘿 放开我 放我走
- Come on.  - Hey, let me go! Get off me!
妈的！
Shit!
威尔？ 威尔？ 起来 走
Will? Will? Let's go. Come on. Get up.
你行吗？威尔？
Are you okay, Will?
头伤到了 撞到了
Head hurts. I just got the shit kicked out of me.
妈妈在哪儿？乔许在哪儿？
Where's Mom? Where's Josh?
我不确定
I'm not sure where they are.
什么？
What?
我问你 妈妈在哪儿？乔许在哪儿？我离开时你和他们在一起
I asked you, "Where's Mom? Where's Josh?" I left them with you.
一帮人上了船
Men came on the boat.
用枪顶着我头 带走了妈妈 乔许和达拉
They put a gun to my head, and they took your mother and Josh and Dara.
- 到底发生了什么  - 抱歉
- What the hell is happening?  - I'm sorry.
- 你抱歉什么 为什么  - 抱歉
- Why are you sorry? What?  - I'm sorry.
威尔, 我不接待福音四重奏或者毕加索专家
Will, I don't book gospel quartets and Picasso experts.
那不是我在使馆的工作
It's not the job I do at the Embassy.
唯一真实的事我为政府工作已经很久了
The only thing that's true is that I've worked for the government a long time.
那你做什么？
So what do you do?
是特勤处
It's a branch of the Agency.
特别的特勤处
It's a special branch of the Agency.
- 妈妈和乔许失踪了  - 不像你想的
- And Mom and Josh are gone.  - Not like you think.
- 别把我当傻瓜  - 我没有
- Just don't treat me like an idiot.  - I'm not.
- 你有! 妈妈和乔许失踪了  - 我没骗你
- You are! Mom and Josh are gone.  - I'm not treating...
你是中情局的人  你不知道他们在哪儿？
You're CIA and you don't know where they are?
对不起
I'm sorry.
跟你做的事有关吗？
Is it something you did?
可能是
It may be, yes.
对不起 威尔
I'm sorry, Will.
我没法向你解释
There's no way I could ever explain that to you.
但是 我们会找回你妈妈 乔许 达拉
But we're gonna get your mother back and Josh back and Dara back.
先休息一下
Try and get some rest.
- 嘿  - 马丁 是你吗？
- Hey.  - Marty, is that you?
- 是我  - 怎么了？
- Yeah, it's me.  - What's going on?
- 我现在路上  - 发生什么了？
- I'm on my way now.  - What's happening?
- 你在哪儿？  - 我在家 现在是凌晨三点呀
- Where are you?  - I'm at home. It's 3:00 in the morning.
我需要见你
I need to see you.
出发吧
Yeah. Let's go. Come on.
我需要你来开车
I need you to drive.
迪亚哥 我要去见卡瑞克 我需要你的帮助
Diego, I'm gonna meet Carrack. I need your help.
我过会儿打给你
I'll call you later.
妈妈知道吗？
Does Mom know?
她知道 她知道所有的事情
Yeah, she knows. She knows everything.
- 她是我妻子  - 你怎么不告诉我这些呢？
- She's my wife.  - How could you not tell me this?
不可能告诉你  不可能 威尔
There was no way to tell you. No way, Will.
告诉你我做什么永远都不会是正确的事
It would have never been right to tell you what I do.
那是谁？
Who's that?
朋友
A friend.
坐着别动
Just sit tight.
你没问题吗？
You gonna be all right?
你是个好儿子
You're a great son.
马上就回来
Be back in a second.
- 你还好吗？  - 不好
- Are you okay?  - No.
怎么啦？你受伤了？
What's going on? Are you hurt?
你做了什么？你给我设局？
What did you do? You set me up?
- 设局了没有？  - 你给我设局了没有？
- Did I set you up?  - Did you set me up?
- 马丁 你在说什么呐？  - 他们从船上带走了拉瑞和乔许
- Marty, what are you talking about?  - They took Laurie and Josh off the boat.
谁干的？
Who did?
你不告诉我 即没法儿帮你 马丁
I can't help you if you don't talk to me, Marty.
谁带走拉瑞？谁干的？
Who took Laurie? Who did?
我们拿了他们公文箱的那些家伙  他们要拿回公文箱
The guys we took the briefcase from. They want it back.
- 妈的  - 他们是谁 珍？
- Shit.  - Who are they, Jean?
他们给我24小时 否则就杀了他们
They gave me 24 hours, or they're going to kill them.
公文箱在哪儿？
Where's the briefcase?
公文箱已经上交了 没了
The briefcase went straight up the line. It's gone.
卡瑞克, 现在别惹我
Carrack, don't fuck with me right now.
- 不  - 我试试
- No?  - I'll try.
- 不行  - 我试试
- No, that's it?  - I'll try.
- 好 我现在走  - 马丁 我愿意帮你
- Okay, then I'm gonna go.  - Marty, I want to help you.
直接上缴了 已经不在我这儿了
It went straight up the line. I don't have it anymore.
你必须解决
You need to fix this.
我尽全力 马丁
I'll do my best, Marty.
爸？
Dad?
上帝
God.
处理一下尸体
Deal with the body.
- 喂？  - 情况怎么样？
- Hello?  - What's the status?
- 有人要杀我  - 让汤姆接电话
- Someone's trying to kill me.  - Put Tom on the phone.
- 有人向我父亲开枪  - 告诉汤姆 他还有不到21小时了
- Someone shot my father.  - Tell Tom he has less than 21 hours.
汤姆是谁？你到底是谁？
Who's Tom? Who the hell are you?
你全家在我手上
The guy who has your family.
哪儿有……
Where do you have...
嘿！嘿！不！
Hey! Hey, hey! No!
有个家伙要杀我！
There's a guy who's trying to kill me!
有个家伙要杀我！  有个家伙要杀我！
Hold on, this guy's going to kill me! There's a guy trying to kill me!
他妈的！
Damn it!
好 我
Okay, I...
我是美国人！
I'm American!
能帮助我吗？
Can you help me?
没有证据说马丁 苏属于我们在西班牙的任何机构
There's no evidence of a Martin Shaw with any of our agencies in Spain.
他告诉我们他是文化处随员
He told us he was a cultural attache.
你刚才说他不是
I thought you said that he wasn't.
我父亲死了 被处决了 被暗杀了
My father is dead. Executed. Assassinated.
苏先生 这里有一个关于你的抓捕证
Mr. Shaw, there's a local warrant for your arrest.
- 指控你杀害一名警官  - 等等 等等 不是 不是
- It claims you killed a police officer.  - Wait, hold it, hold it. No. No.
听着 杀我父亲的家伙追杀我横跨半个城区
Look, the guy who shot my father was shooting at me halfway across the city.
我们会帮你找律师
We can assist you in securing legal counsel
保护你做为美国公民的权利
and protecting your rights as an American citizen.
我没杀警察
Look, I did not kill that cop.
但是你知道 我们没有这个时间
But you know what? We don't have time for this.
我家人才没有时间 求你帮帮我
My family doesn't have the time. Will you please help me? Please?
我建议你接受我们的帮助找个律师
I suggest you accept our help getting you legal counsel.
- 有没有别人我可以谈谈的  - 冷静点儿
- Is there someone else I can talk to?  - Just calm down.
所有人都对我说冷静点儿
All anyone ever says to me is calm down.
安静 安静
Tranquilo, tranquilo.
我家人被绑架了
My family has been kidnapped,
我没杀人却被通缉
and I am wanted for a murder I did not commit.
是
Yes?
是 长官
Yes, ma'am.
现在
Right now, in fact.
有人要见你
Someone needs to talk to you.
跟我们来 苏先生
Come with us, Mr. Shaw.
威尔？ 这是珍
Will? It's Jean.
珍 卡瑞克  我和你父亲一起工作
Jean Carrack. I worked with your father.
如果你伸出左手 我会看到一个白色疤痕
You know, I bet if you raise your left hand, I will see a big white scar
横跨你手掌
running right across your palm.
你十岁那年为我调酒时留下的
You got that making me a martini when you were 10.
- 你不记得了？  - 是 我记得你
- Don't you remember?  - Hey, yeah. I remember you.
你父亲为了一个艰巨的任务离开了你们家
Look, your father has left your family in a tough spot.
我愿意帮助
I'd like to help.
你干嘛不上车 我们去把这些搞清楚呢？
Why don't you get in the car and we'll figure this out?
好 如果你没杀他 谁杀的？
Okay, if you didn't kill him, who did?
我在那儿是帮他
I was there to help him.
我想保护他 但是他不听我的
I was trying to protect him, but he wouldn't listen to me.
你父亲不是个善于倾听的人
He was not a great listener, your father.
上车以后我会告诉你我知道的一起
I'll tell you everything I know when you get in the car.
威尔 来吧
Will. Come on.
你要救你的家人啊？还有个期限呐
Do you want to save your family? Because there's an expiration date on that.
来吧 威尔
Come on, Will.
为了你家人 你父亲在和什么人打交道？
So who was your father dealing with about your family?
同谁联络
Who was his contact?
你说过你会讲的
I thought you said you were gonna do the talking.
我要帮你 即必须知道和谁打交道
If I'm going to help you, I have to figure out who I'm dealing with.
他给谁打过电话？  他去见过谁？
Did he call anyone? Did he meet anyone?
- 你没事吧？  - 我想我病了
- Are you all right?  - I think I'm gonna be sick.
- 真的  - 真的
- Really?  - Really.
停车
Pull over.
好点儿吗？
Better?
好了 孩子 走吧
All right, kid, come on. Let's go.
小心
Senor!
小兔崽子
You little...
别管他
Forget him.
走 我们先找另外一个
Come on, let's go. We'll just get the other one first.
嘿！离开哪里！  离开哪里！
Hey! Get away from there! Get away from there!
什么？
What?
别这么做 认真的
Don't do this to me. Seriously.
请你 我……
Please. I'm...
谢谢
Thank you.
是？
Yes?
喂？你是…… 喂？
Hello? Are you... Hello?
告诉你儿子我要同汤姆讲话
Tell your son I want to speak to Tom.
- 威尔？  - 妈！
-  Will?  - Mom!
妈妈 你没事吧？
Mom, are you okay?
让你父亲接 我现在需要同他讲话
Put your father on the phone. I need to speak to him now.
妈妈
Mom,
你不能
you can't.
让他接电话
Just put him on the phone.
妈妈 我没办法让他接电话
Mom, I can't put him on the phone.
威尔 照我说的做
Will, just do as I say.
妈妈
Mom, I can't.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
妈妈 他们把他杀了
Mom, they've killed him.
不 不
No! No!
嘿！嘿！安静
Hey! Hey! Calm down.
汤姆和我有协议 公文箱还我 要么你们家死
Tom and I had an agreement. My briefcase or your family's dead.
听着 我不知道什么行李箱、公文箱乱七八糟的
Listen, I don't know anything about your suitcase or briefcase or anything.
放了我家人
Just let my family go.
- 这样争取不到时间  - 什么？！
- This is not going to buy any more time.  - What?
提醒汤姆我有筹码
Remind Tom what is at stake.
我父亲已经死了 他的名字叫马丁
Look, my dad is dead and his name was Martin.
你找错人啦
You've got the wrong guy.
告诉汤姆 下午六点 太阳门广场
Tell Tom. 6:00 PM. Puerta del Sol.
要么还公文箱 要么你家人死
My briefcase or your family's dead.
喂 你会讲英语吗？
Hello. Do you speak any English?
一点点 怎么帮您？
A little bit. How can I help you?
我名字叫威尔 苏 我正在找迪亚哥
My name is Will Shaw. I'm just looking for Diego.
他是我父亲的朋友
He was a friend of my father's.
能给我你的地址吗？
Can you give me your address, please?
是
Yes.
克鲁街
Cruz Street.
34号 502室 马德里
34, Suite 502, Madrid.
嘿
Hi.
嘿 你好
Hi, how are you?
能为您做什么？
What can I do for you?
- 我们通过电话  - 嗯？
- We spoke on the phone.  - Mmm-hmm.
你给我的地址到这儿
You gave me the directions here.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我能帮您吗？
Can I help you?
我要见迪亚哥 克德拉
I need to speak to Diego Caldera.
嘿 威尔  感觉好些吗？
Hey, Will. You feeling better now?
喔!喔!
Whoa! Whoa!
把枪放下 把枪放下 把枪放下
Put the gun down! Put the gun down! Put the gun down!
我只会讲英语
I only speak goddamn English!
你想杀我叔叔
You want to kill my uncle!
谁是你叔叔？
Who the hell is your uncle?
迪亚哥 克德拉是你叔叔吗？
Is Diego Caldera your uncle?
是 枪在包裹里来的
Yeah. This cabron comes in here with a gun
坐下 闭嘴 等我叔叔回来
and tells me to sit down and shut up, waiting for my uncle to come in.
今天早上 这家伙的朋友谋杀了我父亲
This guy's friends murdered my father this morning.
你父亲被谋杀了？
Your father was murdered?
就是我来这里的原因
That's why I'm here.
我爸爸给这里打了好多次电话 找迪亚哥
My dad called this office at least a dozen times looking for Diego.
- 你叔叔当时在哪里？  - 什么？
- Where is your uncle then?  - What?
看 好？这家伙
Look, okay? This guy,
他的人来这里找你叔叔
his people came looking here for your uncle.
他们下一个要去哪里找？
Where are they going to look next?
你真的要在这里等他的人上来吗？
Do you really want to be here when his pals turn up?
来吧 我们必须找到你叔叔
Come on. We gotta find your uncle.
- 开着的  - 好 好 我来
- It's open.  - Okay, okay, I've got it.
新闻全是这孩子的
This kid is all over the damn news.
今天早上你为什么不做了他呢？
Why didn't you take care of him this morning?
快点儿 迪克生 接电话
Come on, Dixon, answer your phone.
别碰！
Don't do it!
嘿 威尔 惊奇吧
Hi, Will. Surprise.
把枪放下 威尔
Put the gun down, Will.
你害怕了
You're scared,
受惊吓的人拿枪早我面前晃 真的会吓到我
and scared people holding guns in my face, that scares me.
这次谈话会很伤脑筋
Well, this is going to be a nerve-wracking conversation.
我可以坐下吗？
May I sit down?
怎么样？
So,
我能为你做什么？
what can I do for you?
为什么杀他？
Why did you kill him?
如果我们换个位置
If our situations were reversed,
相信我 你父亲会做同样的事情
believe me, your father would've done the exact same thing.
为什么杀他？
Why did you kill him?
你父亲要把一些东西还给我们的敌人
Your father wanted to give something back to our enemies
关系到国家安全
that's a matter of national security.
你是说公文箱？
You mean the briefcase?
他正准备背叛国家 威尔
He was about to betray his country, Will.
出卖我们 他自己的团队
And betray us, his team.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
是吗？老实讲 孩子
- Really?  - Honestly, kid,
我们才不在乎
we don't give a shit.
也许我比你更了解他
Maybe I knew him better than you did.
我要见我家人
I want to see my family.
不在我手上
I don't have your family.
在谁手上？
Who does?
很抱歉告诉你 是一些恐怖分子
I'm sorry to say that some terrorists do.
威尔, 我最不想牵扯你进来
Will, you are the last person I want to get more involved in this right now.
但是我需要你帮助
But I need your help.
你要告诉我还有谁 他见过 说过这事
I need you to tell me who else he saw or spoke to about this.
你给我我要的
You give me what I need,
我会动用所有的力量帮你就会你家人
I will pull out all the stops to help you get your family back.
你要告诉他们 我父亲已经死了 我跟这事儿一点关系都没有
You need to tell them that my father's dead and that I've got nothing to do with this.
我只是要就会我家人
I just want to save my family!
对
Right.
我想我肯定是欠你什么
So, I certainly think we owe you something.
等等 坐下
Wait, wait, wait. Sit down!
跑 快
Go! Come on!
走 走！
Go, go!
快呀！
Come on!
该死的！
God damn it!
让开！
Get out of the way!
走！走！走！
Go! Go! Go!
我们要找条路下去
We gotta find a way down!
没路下去！
There's no way down!
上帝！
God!
- 你要干嘛？  - 胳膊举起来
- What are you doing?  - Get your arms up.
- 好 用胳膊夹住  - 不 等等 这不行的
- Okay, hold that under your arm.  - No, no. Wait! Are you kidding me?
- 相信我 只有这样下去  - 不 不 绝对不行
- Trust me. This is the only way down.  - No, no, no. No way!
只有这样你才会安全
This is the only way you're going to be safe.
你疯了吗？
No! Are you crazy?
- 露西亚!  - 不 不行！
- Lucia!  - No! No way!
站住 听我说！
Stand still and listen to me!
准备好了吗？
Are you ready for this?
威尔 别扔我下去！
Will! Don't drop me!
哦 上帝呀！
Oh, God!
停！
Stop!
威尔 快呀！
Will! Come on!
快呀！
Come on!
我受伤了
I've been shot.
她在这儿
She's here!
威尔!
Will!
不！
No!
幸运
Lucky.
没事了 没事了  不要去医院
It's fine. It's fine.  No hospital.
没事了  不要去医院
- It's fine.  - No hospital.
不是医院 我有朋友可以帮你
It's not a hospital. My friend can help you here.
你要带我去太阳门广场  好的
You gotta take me to Puerta del Sol. It's fine.
你行吗？
Are you okay?
什么地方？
What is this place?
克里斯 快
Chris, please!
露西亚！怎么啦？
Lucia! What happened?
你一定要带我去太阳门广场 我要找我家人
You gotta take me to Puerta del Sol. I need to find my family.
他们杀了我叔叔
They killed my uncle!
他受伤了 你一定要帮我们
This guy's wounded! You have to help me!
不 带他走 你会给我们惹麻烦的
No, take him away. You'll get me into trouble!
你学过医 帮帮他！
You go to medical school, help him!
我是学生 不是医生
I'm a student, not a doctor.
嘿！
Hey!
克里斯提安娜! 在干什么呀？
Cristiana! What's going on?
哈比, 打电话给马克斯模 我们需要帮助
Habib, call Maximo, we need help!
他流了好多血 我不知道能他去哪儿？
He's losing lots of blood! I don't have anywhere to take him.
- 什么时候受得伤  - 可能有一个小时了
- When was he shot?  - An hour ago, I think.
别让他睡着了
Keep him awake.
跟我说话 跟我说话！
Talk to me! Please, talk to me!
他们在哪儿？
Where are they?
办公室
In the office.
她以为这是医院吗？
Does she think this is a hospital?
我欠他叔叔人情
I owe her uncle some favors
但他不能带一个流血的家伙到我的夜总会里来
but she can't bring a bleeding guy into my club!
我可没时间在这搅和
I don't have time for this shit!
怎么啦 姑娘们？
What's going on, girls?
马克斯模 求你了
Maximo, please.
马克斯模, 迪亚哥被杀了
Maximo, Diego has been killed.
小伙子救了我的命
This guy saved my life!
他父亲也被杀了
His father's been killed too.
马克斯模 给我点儿伏特加 给我的手消消毒
Maximo, hand me that vodka. I need to sterilize my hands.
露西亚 告诉他 这会很痛的
Lucia, tell him this is going to hurt a lot.
我要找到子弹在哪儿
I need to see if there's a bullet.
- 她在说什么？  - 她说别担心
- What's she saying?  - She says not to worry.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
很好 没有弹片在里面 我现在要止血
Perfect! There's no bullet. Now I have to stop the bleeding.
没有子弹  没有子弹
There is no bullet. There is no bullet.
保佑 保佑 保佑
Please, please, please. Okay.
你要喝一杯吗？朋友 反正我要
You need a drink, my friend? I do.
弟兄们 按住他
Guys, hold him tight!
- 她在干什么？她在干什么？  - 好 她在止血
- What's she doing? What's she doing?  - Okay, she's gonna stop the bleeding.
干得好 朋友
Well done. Well done, my friend.
哦 我要去吐了
Oh! I'm going to puke.
为什么要杀我叔叔？
Why did they kill my uncle?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能因为我父亲找过他
Probably because my father reached out to him.
我不知道 抱歉
I don't know. I'm sorry.
为什么你手机里会有汤姆 Keaton的照片？
Why do you have a photo of Tom Keaton on your phone?
那是我父亲 那是马丁 苏
That's my father. That's Martin Shaw.
合适你父亲？
He's your father?
是
Yes.
- 他死了？你确定他死了？  - 是
- Is he dead? Are you sure he's dead?  - Yes.
是 我对你讲过了
Yes, I told you.
你认识我父亲？你们是朋友？
Did you know my father? Were you friends?
高于一切的朋友
Friends before anything else.
我的一生
All my life.
哦 上帝我不能待在这儿 我要去找我的家人
Oh, God. I can't stay here. I've gotta find my family.
你要去哪儿找？
Where do you need to go?
太阳门广场
To Puerta del Sol.
所以 你叫你爸爸 马丁？
So you called your father Martin?
不是我叫他 那是他的名字
I didn't call him that. That was his name.
你知道他干什么吗？
Do you even know what he did?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
他做什么谋生？
What he did for a living.
他说他是商业咨询顾问
He said he was a business consultant.
商业咨询顾问 那么有钱
Business consultant. That's rich.
你呢？你是干什么的？
What about you? What do you do?
我原来有家小公司
I used to run a small company.
做什么的小公司？
And what did your small company do?
商业咨询
Business consultants.
有其父 有其子
Like father, like son.
好像你和我父亲很熟 怎么会？
So you seem to know my father pretty well. How come?
你和他上床吗？
Were you sleeping with him?
你这么想？
That's what you think?
我不是你……
I wasn't your...
我不知道我该怎么想
I don't know what I'm supposed to think.
我不是你父亲的情人
I wasn't your father's lover.
我母亲是
My mother was.
他也是我父亲
He was my father, too.
你知道他另一个家吗？
Did you know about his other family?
他几乎从不在家
He was hardly around.
有时我觉得 父母越是不在身边
Sometimes I think the more a parent's absent,
你就越爱他们
the more you love them.
下一站 太阳门广场
Next stop, Puerta del Sol.
你也是？
So, you, too?
我还行
I was fine with it.
肯定是
Sure you were.
你母亲呢？
And your mother?
她是什么样子？
What's she like?
我母亲死了
My mother is dead.
对不起
I'm sorry.
威尔！等等！
Will! Wait!
等等
Wait.
- 好  - 我跟你说过了 我需要单独一个人去
- Okay.  - I told you. I need to go alone.
如果你要找我 我会在夜总会
If you need me, I'll be at the club.
就这样
That's all.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我希望你能带他们回来
I hope you will get them back.
把手伸出来 让我能看见
Keep your hands where I can see them.
转过来 跟我走
Turn around and walk with me.
哪儿？
Where?
跟着
Follow me.
你父亲在哪儿？
Where is your father?
我家人在哪儿？
Where's my family?
我告诉你了
I've told you,
一遍又一遍
over and over.
我父亲死了
My father is dead.
如果你不信我
If you don't believe me,
让你的人跟着我进城
then have your guy here really go to town on me.
他肯定会感觉好些的
Sure he'll feel better.
我还是什么他妈的都不知道
And I still won't know a goddamned thing.
即使是真的 也是你的问题
Even if that's true, it's still your problem.
你知道我们怎么会查到这里吗 威尔？
Do you know how we come to this, Will?
两个月前 我的手下发现一个腐化特工
Two months ago, one of my men posed as a corrupt agent
准备向恐怖分子出售敏感情报
willing to sell sensitive pieces of intel to terrorists.
任务是揭发一个中央情报局流氓特工
The mission was to uncover a rogue CIA operative
我们已经知道他是为自己的利益来做交易
we knew was making deals for his own interest.
于是 我的人安排了会面
So my agent arranged a rendezvous.
猜猜谁露面了？
And guess who showed up?
你父亲杀了我的特工
Your father killed my agent
偷走了装有我国非常重要情报的公文箱
and stole a briefcase that held contents vital to my country.
现在 你告诉我说他死了？
And now you tell me he's dead?
特工？
Agent?
或者是恐怖分子
How about terrorist?
恐怖分子？
Terrorist?
我妻子和儿子在特拉维夫咖啡馆里遇到恐怖分子
My wife and son met a terrorist once, in a cafe in Tel Aviv.
一瞬间
In an instant,
他们 和其他15个人
they and 15 others
变成了灰烬
were turned to ash.
所以问题变成了
So the question becomes
是谁要杀你父亲？
who killed your father?
他自己部门的人
People from his own agency.
他们杀了他的朋友 也要杀了我
They killed his friend and they've been trying to kill me, too.
你是说卡瑞克？
You mean Carrack?
是
Yeah.
你们真应该一起聊聊这个
You guys should really get together and chat about this.
我想你该上来…
I think you'd get on really...
大概她想杀了你 因为是目击者
Perhaps she wants to eliminate you as a witness,
还有你家其他人
along with the rest of your family.
归根到底 无论你到哪儿
Bottom line is that, wherever you go,
他们都要抓到你
they'll be hunting you.
那样正合适
And that will suit our purposes fine.
- 威尔!  - 威尔!
- Will!  - Will!
- 你还活着！  - 弟兄们！
- You're alive!  -  Guys!
- 有人伤着你们吗？  - 威尔 你没事吧？
- Has anyone hurt you?  -  Will, you're okay!
讽刺的是
The irony is,
如果你父亲的杀手们正在追杀证人
if your father's killers are trying to eliminate witnesses,
那么 能让你家人活命的正是他们的囚禁
the only thing keeping your family alive right now is their captivity.
所以我的办法是
So here is the deal.
你出去 将她引出来
I need you out there to draw her to you.
我们知道有些买主已经来了
We know that some potential buyers are in town.
感觉交易就在眼前
So we feel that the sale is imminent.
既然她那么想杀了你们
If she really wants to kill you all,
我只需要待在你们附近
I just need to stay close to you.
但是必须说清楚 如果我没能在交易前抓住卡瑞克
But just so we're clear, if I don't stop Carrack before it's sold,
我不会继续扣押你的家人
I won't keep your family any longer.
我会放了他们 卡瑞克 会杀了他们
I'll release them, and Carrack will kill them.
明白了？
Understood?
弟兄们！
Guys!
威尔！等等！
Will! Wait!
放开我！
Just get off of me!
嘿i！把手拿开 放开我
Hey! Get your hands off me! Get off me!
让我走！
Let me go!
嘿 兄弟
Hey, man.
我要见 露西亚
I need to see Lucia.
来 我带你去
Come. I'll take you.
威尔
Will.
我见到他们了 他们还活着
I've seen them. They're alive.
我要她来找我
I need to get her coming after me.
这不难 反正她一直都想抓我们
It shouldn't be hard, 'cause she's trying to track me down anyway.
她要杀掉每个知情人
She wants to kill anyone who knew anything about it.
以色列人说买主今晚就到
And the Israeli said that the likely buyers are in town tonight.
所以我们必须马上行动 他们随时可能成交
So we gotta move, 'cause the deal could happen any time.
嘿
Hey.
- 给你  - 谢谢
- For you.  - Thank you.
你听到多少？
How much did you hear?
加上以前露西亚告诉我的  够了
Along with what Lucia told me before? Enough.
卡瑞克 这个婊子
This bitch, Carrack,
是她杀的 迪亚哥 对吗？
she's the one who killed Diego, right?
我能帮些什么？
So, how can I help?
他们是间谍 对吗？到处都有眼线
They're spies, right? Eyes everywhere?
电话 电子邮件 所有的
Phones, e-mail. Everything.
放一点消息 他们就会找到我们
Let's start a tab. Then they'll find us.
露西亚 等一下 你真的要这么做？
Lucia, wait a second. Are you sure you're ready for this?
你可以带着荣誉感说我的名字
Say my name and you can say it with honor
她今晚不上班
She's not working tonight.
谢谢
Gracias.
你不了解我 你上学的时候
You don't understand me, but when you were in school,
听过布雷尔兔的故事吗？嗯？
you ever hear the story of Brer Rabbit? Huh?
- 这个卖了吗？  - 这个卖了吗？
- Is it sold?  - Is it sold?
基督呀！  你比你父亲还笨！
Jesus Christ! You're dumber than your father.
你究竟要问什么 威尔？
What are you actually asking me, Will?
这个卖了吗？什么卖了？公文箱吗？  还是你家人死了吗？
"Is it sold?" What's sold? The briefcase? Or is your family dead?
因为如果卖了 他们就死了 对吗？
'Cause if it's sold, they're dead. Right?
交易一定会做的
The deal's gonna happen.
唯一能知道地点的办法 就是让我告诉你
And the only way you'll know where is if you make me tell you.
但我什么也不会告诉你
But I ain't telling you shit.
不！
No!
把他弄起来
Get him up!
- 给他松绑  - 他要杀了你 哥们儿
- Untie him! - He'll kill you, man.
威尔!
Will!
放开我！  我们会做的
Get off me! We'll do this!
- 放开我！放开我！  - 我们会做的！
- Get off me! Get off me!  - We'll do this!
卡瑞克在哪儿？回答我！
Where's Carrack? Answer me!
告诉我 她在哪儿？她为什么不在这儿？
Tell me! Where is she? Why isn't she here?
- 她为什么不在这儿？  - 因为！
- Why isn't she here?  - Because!
她是女士
She's a lady.
不像你小妹妹
And ladies, unlike your little sister,
女士会待在家里 男人出去
stay at home while the men go out...
好好修理他！
Kick the shit out of him!
别担心 他会招的  就把他捆起来吧 已经够了
Don't worry. He'll talk.  Just tape him up. We've done enough.
我知道看了这个不舒服 但是有效
I know that it's not easy to watch, but it will work.
- 不 不会的  - 会的
- No, it won't.  - It will.
- 我有个计划  - 胶带弄不住他
- I've got a plan.  - The duct tape won't hold.
我们必须让他走 我们要弄辆车
We have to let him go. We need a car.
- 我不明白  - 向我保证你不会进那边
- I don't understand.  - Promise me you won't go in there.
还是不明白
I still don't understand.
他以为我是白痴 我就装给他看
He thinks I'm an idiot. Let me deliver on that.
爸爸不是叛徒 卡瑞克耍了他
Dad was no traitor. Carrack played him.
也耍了以色列人
Played him and the Israelis.
- 以色列人出动了吗？  - 最好是
- And the Israelis are out there?  - They better be.
在那儿
There.
他们要逃
They are on the move.
跟着他们 如果她出现就告诉我
Stay close to them. Call me if she shows up.
好
Ok.
他跑了
He got away.
以后再处理他
I'll deal with him later.
为了你的命 希望他们没跟来
Let's hope for your sake he doesn't show up.
在那儿 停车
There. Pull over.
小心
Be careful.
- 待在这儿 好？  - 好 你要怎么做？
- Stay here, okay?  - Okay. What are you gonna do?
等他们
Wait for them.
我很高兴你带来了我期望的东西
I'm glad to see you brought what I was expecting.
是 碰到点儿小麻烦 已经摆平了
Yeah, I ran into a little bit of trouble, but it's been dealt with.
嘘！跟我来
Shh! Come with me.
- 我和你们是一边的  - 好
- We're on your side.  - Okay.
好 先生们 准备好了 我们就做生意吧
So, gentlemen, if you're ready, we can do our business.
我怎么确定这是真东西？
How can I be sure this is the real thing?
这直接来自摩萨德特工
It came directly from a Mossad agent.
不行的是 没有证人
Sadly, no eyewitnesses.
不可能找到类似的东西了
You're not gonna find anything else like this one.
嘘！
Shh!
爬到这儿来
Crawl back out of here.
现在我们接管
We'll take over now.
不 告诉我我家人在那儿 否则哪儿也不去
No. Tell me where my family is or I'm not going anywhere.
听着 现在离开 不然我把你扔出去
Listen to me. Leave now or I'll have to drag you out.
- 不  - 离开
- No!  - Leave now!
抓住
Catch.
露西亚! 镇静
Lucia! Calm down.
没事 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
你 威尔？
You, Will?
所有的人
Of all the people
那些要杀我的
who should've killed me.
威尔！她来了
Will! She's coming.
不 不 不
No! No! No!
太业余了！
You amateur!
快 快！走 走！
Hurry up. Hurry up. Go, go, go!
小心!
Watch it!
喔!
Whoo!
快呀  别！
- Come on!  - Please! No!
上帝呀
Jesus!
不 不
No, no, no! No!
该死！
God! Damn!
他们在哪儿？  谁呀？
Where are they? Who?
以色列人 他们在哪儿？
The Israelis. Where are they?
妈的！
Shit!
她在哪儿？她在哪儿？
Where is she? Where is she?
她在那
She's there!
不 不 不
No, no, no! Wait, wait! Don't!
快
Come on!
现在谁该赔我的车？
Who's going to pay for my car now?
- 露西亚！出来吧！快！  - 什么？
- Lucia! Get out. Come on, come on!  - What?
好吧 就这样啦
All right! That's it!
我已经烦了 快呀
I'm getting sick of this. Come on.
她来了 她来了
She's coming! She's coming!
快呀
Come on!
该死的！
God damn!
卡瑞克 婊子！
Carrack, you bitch!
哦 威尔
Oh, Will.
真够乱的
What a mess.
看来你需要缝几针
Looks like you're gonna need some more stitches.
你那个要死的小朋友也是
And your little dead friend, too.
你母亲会吓坏的
Your mother's gonna freak out.
喔！ 那是你父亲的枪？
Aw! Is that your father's gun?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是在找这种东西吗？
You looking for something like this?
威尔！
Will!
我妹妹 她受伤了
My sister. She's hurt back there.
放松点儿 她在去医院的路上
Relax. She's halfway to the hospital.
你父亲 尽管给我惹了很多麻烦
Your father, for all the hell he caused us,
他会以你为骄傲的
would be proud of you.
我家人怎样了？
What about my family?
哦 上帝呀！
Oh, my God!
什么都不懂的孩子 你自己掌握的不错
You handled yourself pretty well out there for a kid who knows shit.
我必须告诉你 我被你吓着了
I have to tell you, I was impressed.
谢谢你帮我们清理烂摊子
Thanks for helping us clean up our own mess.
意思是我可以回家了？
Does this mean I can go home now?
肯定 怎么都行
Sure. Whatever.
但你应该考虑一下其他业务
But I think you should really consider another line of work.
你知道 你父亲是个正直的人
You know, your father was an honest man.
他走了我很难过
I'm sorry he's gone.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想问个问题？
Could I ask you something?
说
Shoot.
公文箱里到底是什么？
What the hell was in the briefcase?
只有一个办法能回答
There's only one way I can answer that.
我要去看我家人了
I've gotta go see my family.
嘿i
Hey.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你对她讲过我了 对吗？
You told her about me, right?
好像不重要了
It didn't really seem important.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
你应该介绍你自己
You should go and introduce yourself.
她是你妹妹
She is your sister.
她是我妹妹
She is my sister.